I don't know that I've ever
我不知道我曾经
been able to do anything.
可以做什么事情
I say it as a sort of,
我这么说
because I'm aware that it can be a strength
是因为我知道这可能是一种优点
but it can also be a weakness
也可能是一种缺点
because the focus is obsessive
因为成为众人的焦点令人着迷
and so when I go for something,
所以当我要做某事的时候
I go for it at the expense of everything else.
我会对每件事都倾尽全力
And I love what I do, simply,
说白了 就是热爱我所从事的职业
and I feel so lucky that
我感到非常幸运
I'm allowed to do it
我能成为演员
and that I get to do it for a living
同时还能以演戏为生
and cinema and theater have had
电影院、剧院对我一生
such a profound effect on me in my life.
都产生了深远的影响
It's just a gut feeling.
这是一种直觉
I think I always trust my gut,
我一直相信我的直觉
that's all I have,
一向如此
even when I'm working.
甚至是在我工作的时候
And you're thinking about the shape of a scene
当你在想场景的布局
and how it should be played
还有场景该如何进行的时候
and your head can often get in the way
你的大脑总会干扰
and you've got to trust your gut.
你得相信你的直觉
And it's just if I'm inspired,
如果我受到启发
if my curiosity is peaked,
如果我非常好奇
and I want to chase this possibility down,
我想追寻这种可能性
that I see in front of me on my desk,
我知道坐在桌子前的
and some of you may have heard me say this before.
有些人可能之前已经听我说过
And I'm embarrassed to say,
我很不好意思地说
I always speak in metaphors,
我总是通过比喻来说明
I don't know how to speak in any other way
因为我不知道用其他方式如何表达
and for me, acting is kind of like playing the piano
对我来说 表演有点像弹钢琴
and if the piano is the human condition
如果把钢琴比作人体的话
and we all have every single note
我们都有每一个音符
on that 88 key board within us
存在于我们体内的88个琴键
and for me, every role,
对我来说 每个角色
I want to be able to play every note
我都希望能演好它
and sometimes if a character or a story
如果一个角色或故事
seem to stretch me in some way,
在某种程度上吸引我
seems to offer up an experience that is new,
给我一种全新的体验
that is a different chord or a different tune,
一种不同的和弦或曲调
that is real and true,
那种情深意切的
and human and accessible,
深入人心的体验
and no matter how joyous or loving or warm,
无论多么欢乐、热爱或温暖
or how dark or painful,
亦或多么黑暗、痛苦
if it seems like an interesting shape to inhabit,
如果它是一个有趣的角色
I know if I'm running towards it already.
我知道我已经为它准备好了
Okay, couple of basic things,
好的 一些基本的事情
be on time,
守时
never underestimate the
千万不要低估
importance of punctuality,
守时的重要性
be prepared,
做好准备
you can never be over-prepared
准备得再充分都不为过
and be true to yourself
做真实的自己
and if you have something
如果你有事情
that you want to say
迫不及待
that you've been burning to say,
想说的事情
don't ever let anyone tell
永远不要让任何人告诉你
you that you can't say it.
你不能说